Dewan M.I. Mukto

dm@mux8.com | LinkedIn: dewanmukto | GitHub: dwmk | dewanmukto.github.io

About

Dewan M.I. Mukto is a multipotentialite interested in maximizing profits and efficiency under the influence of his ENFP-T MBTI personality type. He is notable for his contributions to the fields of art, literature, science, and technology. Since 2014, Dewan Mukto has been active in creating various types of content and tasks including videos and vlogs, music production, graphic designing, UI and UX designing, programming, web development, app development, game development, writing novels, poetry and books, 3D animation, shader scripting, fashion and merch design, digital marketing, project management, motivational speaking, customer retention, entrepreneurship, brand building, academic teaching and training, and research upon the fields of AI, mathematics, economics, and psychology.

Education

BRAC University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Oct 2024-Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Memorial University of Newfoundland and Labrador, St. John's, Canada

Sep 2020-Dec 2023

BSc in Computer Science, GPA: 3.06/4.00, 83 Credits

Anandaniketan School, Sylhet, Bangladesh

2006-2020

Pearson Edexcel IGCSE: 9s in Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Mathematics, ICT, English, Bengali, Further Pure Mathematics

IAS: A in Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Further Mathematics

IA2: A in Mathematics, B in Physics, C in Chemistry

Experience

Mux AI, Remote, Bangladesh

Jul 2023–Present

Web Developer, Software Developer, Marketing Strategist, Graphic Designer, UI/UX Designer

Sherwin-Williams, St. John's, Canada

Jul 2022–Jun 2023

Sales Associate

Jungle Jim's Eatery, St. John's, Canada

Jun 2022–Aug 2022

Kitchen Helper

Mark's, St. John's, Canada

Oct 2021–Feb 2022, Jul 2022–Aug 2022

Sales Associate

Dewan IELTS, Remote, Bangladesh

 $\mathrm{Jan}\ 2021\text{--}\mathrm{Feb}\ 2022$

IELTS Trainer

Mux Anime Studios, Remote, Bangladesh

Nov 2019–Feb 2022

Director, Animator, Marketing Strategist, Recruiter

Pathantula Govt Primary School, Sylhet, Bangladesh

Apr 2018-Nov 2018

English Language Teacher

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, C, Fortran, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, OpenGL, Lua, Kotlin, NextJS, Vite, Selenium

Technical: Web SaaS Development, UI/UX Design, Figma, Git, Linux, SEO, Image/Video Editing, Microsoft Office, Canva, WordPress, Wix, Webflow, Bubble.io

Business: Brand Marketing, Digital Marketing, Project Management, Product Design, Copywriting, Customer Engagement, Lead Generation

Passive: Leadership, Creativity, Problem Solving, Teaching, Motivational Speaking, Entrepreneurship, Statistical Analysis

Publications

In The Wildest Dimensions (2024): Psychological thriller novel

Synaesthetic Symphonies (2023): Aesthetic poetry anthology

Dead Man Alive (2023): Horror/paranormal novella IELTS Guide (2023): Guide for IELTS preparation Cooper Black (2022): Action/science-fiction novel

Achievements

National Builders of Tomorrow Award, The Daily Star Awards, 2020

Pearson Edexcel Higher Achievers' Award, 2020

IELTS Overall Score: 8.5, 2019

Bronze Award, Duke of Edinburgh Awards, 2019

National Rounder (1st Rank in Sylhet), 2nd English Olympiad, 2018

National Rounder, 13th Bangladesh Astro-Olympiad, 2018

National Rounder, 1st English Olympiad, Jan 2017

Honorable Mention, 9th Bangladesh Physics Olympiad, 2019

3rd Prize, CAM SUST Astro Carnival, 2014

2nd Prize, Charupath Art Exhibition, 2011

Projects

Acado: Webapp for creating, previewing, and exporting academic assignments with APA-7 format (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, Vite, jsPDF, html2canvas)

MizuCV: Online CV builder for creating and exporting CVs (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, Vite, jsPDF, html2canvas)

BRACU Course-to-Routine Builder: Real-time course section comparison tool for students (HTML, TailwindCSS, JS)

Mux Social: Open social networking platform without external interference (HTML, TailwindCSS, NextJS, PostgreSQL, Neon DB, Vercel Blob)

Disorder: Anonymous peer-to-peer chat and file-sharing platform with no persistent storage (HTML, TailwindCSS, PeerJS)